Christian Martinez

Senior Frontend Engineer

Carrer del Bruc 94, 08009, Barcelona, Barcelona Spain

☐ christian.dario.martinez@gmail.com ☐ (+34) 634854678

My purpose is to use my knowledge in both Software and Product Development to make a difference in teams and products. I believe that with my versatility, my experience, and my 'keep-learning attitude', I'm capable of improving not only the quality of a certain source code but the processes involved and the coherence in software teams.

SKILLS

Master Advanced

javascript | es6 | html5 | git react | redux | css | styled-components |

styled-jsx | react-testing-library

Intermediate Beginner

node | nextjs | react native | mysql | docker | aws

mongodb

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Manager at FREE NOW (formerly mytaxi)

July 2019 - Current

https://www.free-now.com

Skills acquired: hypothesis testing | user-testing | discovery and delivery | tableau | sql | react | git

- Building reports and tools to ensure proper tasks and data tracking
- Understanding and defining hypotheses/problems worth solving
- Defining the product roadmap and prioritizing the backlog work of the technical team
- Aligning both Discovery and Delivery teams to make sure they understand the 'why are we doing what we're doing'
- Ensuring product quality of the team's deliverables

Senior Frontend Engineer at myTaxi - The Taxi App

July 2017 - March 2020

https://www.mytaxi.com

Skills acquired: react | react native | redux | styled-components | docker | node.js | git | flow & typescript

Implemented changes on products related to FREE NOW Driver Registration and internal

- tooling using React, Redux, styled-components, and react-testing-lib
- Implemented changes on an internal reusable components library used by several tools across the company
- Implemented changes on a custom shareable React-Native lib used by Driver App
- Provided mentoring, guidance, and support for junior developers in good testing practices, including unit, integration, and E2E tests.

Senior Frontend Engineer | Web UI Team Leader for at Globant

July 2017 - February 2018

http://www.espn.com/fantasy

Skills acquired: react | react storybook | mobx | styled-jsx | nextjs | enzyme & chai (for frontend testing) | css | css flexbox | git

- Managed and mentored a remote team of four Web UI developers
- Led the Web UI team through sprints to deliver features requested by ESPN in the agreed timeline
- Implemented features for the new React-based ESPN fantasy baseball web draft client from scratch.
- Implemented code changes in the product using React, Mobx and Next as base UI technologies
- Participated in the architecture, pattern, and code styles throughout the main product

Full Stack Engineer at Gosoft S.A

March 2016 - May 2017

Skills acquired: javascript | google analytics | angularjs | ionic | sass | c# using razor views, .net core, and entity framework | sql management studio | git

- Performed full-stack development on two projects (CocoBongo.com rebuild and CocoBongo Entrance Checker app) with Javascript, AngularJS, Ionic, C#, and SQL using TDD techniques.
- Implemented Cocobongo's new tracking system for buyer experience optimization with AngularJS and Google Analytics
- Implemented customer design changes across the entire UI of the project.
- Defined and implemented new features/A-B testings for the website that improved Google AdWords campaigns investment
- Using Google Analytics to analyze interaction and web site usage across the project
- Implemented/maintained full backend code in C# (API coding/integrations and SQL DB schema)

Frontend Engineer at Gosur

October 2014 - March 2016

http://www.gosur.com

- Implemented new features using Web development languages (HTML5, CSS, and Javascript) for multiple projects across the company, with extensive browser support (Internet Explorer 8 and above) for mobile, tablet, and desktop devices.
- Worked side by side with designers to bring design ideas into reality
- Improved the SEO and overall web performance across all the company products by implementing changes on the frontend infrastructure in a rapid-development environment
- Included analytics events to UI components in order to track user behavior
- Collaborated with the Backend team in features E2E, API's definitions and testing

Software Engineer at Intel Corporation

September 2011 - September 2014

http://www.intel.com

Skills acquired: javascript | angularjs | node.js | sails.js | ionic | html & css | c++ | python | java | mysql | mongodb | android | qit

- Developed End to end Android + Web App proof the concept for an e-commerce service on the Tizen OS, featuring location based behavior.
- Implementing code using technologies in both backend (nodejitsu, nodes, sailsjs) and frontend (bootstrap, angularjs, leaflet)
- Developed some of the android screens as embedded (webkit) HTML angularjs backend served pages
- Participated in projects related to eCommerce platforms, open-source initiatives (Openstack, and client-side applications)
- Performed Scrum Master tasks in some of the teams

Junior Software Engineer at Intel Corporation

April 2010 - August 2011

Skills acquired: javascript | c++ | bitrock (windows installers) | windows registry knowledge | .net framework

- Performed development task on a Windows client application (based on C++ and Javascript)
- Performed changes on Windows installers for different devices and configurations
- Participated as security development contact, learning and following security procedures that assured the security level of the product.
- Promoted to Semi-Senior Software Engineer after excelling in both soft (got a 'Discipline Role Mode' award from the company) and hard skills (software development in C++).

EDUCATION

MSc Degree in Computer Engineering at Universidad Nacional de Córdoba

- 2010

♥ Córdoba, (Argentina) Córdoba

LANGUAGES

English Fluent Spanish

Native speaker